David Garner

Software Developer

<u>dprgarner@gmail.com</u> · <u>Github</u> · <u>LinkedIn</u>

I'm a full-stack web developer and technical team lead based in London. My primary focus is front-end development with React, but I also have considerable professional experience in back-end development with Node.js, Python, and Django. I place a strong emphasis on quality in all of my code, and consider unit testing and code review to be essential parts of the development process.

Skills

- Front-end: React, Redux, TypeScript, RxJS, Sass, Styled Components, Webpack, Recent ECMAScript Features, Responsive Design, jQuery
- Back-end: Node.js, Python, Docker, Express, Django, Solr, Elasticsearch
- AWS: CloudFormation, CloudWatch, Fargate, Lambda, CloudFront, Fargate
- Testing: Mocha, Jest, Selenium, React Testing Library, TDD, BDD, pytest
- Source control and CI/CD: Git, Jenkins, TeamCity, Gitlab CI, Subversion
- Command line tools: Vim, Bash, common CLI utilities (sed, make, grep, etc.)
- Process management: Scrum, Kanban, Jira, Trello

Employment History

2020–present: Senior Front-end Lead, then Technical Front-end Lead at QMetric, London, UK

I took ownership of the JavaScript codebases within a home insurance platform.

- I maintained and extended a customer-facing app and a backoffice app for purchasing and modifying home insurance policies, with front-ends and backends-for-frontends implemented in React, Express, TypeScript, and RxJS.
- I provided technical leadership, architecture design, and support on a wide range of parallel projects and initiatives, including the front-end rebuilds of the insurance risk form, the quote landing page, and the payments page, as well as the introduction of user-behaviour-tracking analytics and A/B testing.
- I worked with business analysts and delivery managers to break down high-level business requirements into self-contained user stories for development.
- I participated in large-scale architecture discussions with the other tech leads and tech principals to plan the evolution of our cloud-native, event-driven, microservice-architectured insurance platform, implemented primarily in Java with Domain Driven Design.
- I conducted interviews for candidate front-end developers, as well as setting and marking takehome assessments.
- I organised and conducted onboardings, team training meetings, and technical design discussions within a fully-remote team.
- I initiated and assisted with multiple tech-debt initiatives, including the migration of the codebase away from RxJS, the Docker containerisation of the legacy services, and the introduction of browser-side error monitoring and reporting.
- I designed, prototyped, and implemented a Microfrontend architecture to support multiple teams developing the same front-end web application in parallel.

2015–20: Software Developer, then Engineering Lead (2019-20) at Mintel, London, UK

I gained a wide range of experience with legacy and new codebases primarily using React, Redux, Django, Solr, and Elasticsearch. I worked on multiple projects, including:

- Apps for aggregating and presenting direct marketing data and consumer survey data into tables, charts, and dashboards;
- Apps for searching, reading, and generating presentations from long-form articles of market research analysis;
- Internal tools for browser-based Selenium testing, visual regressions testing, and internal front-end libraries for implementing cross-company stylistic consistency.

As the Technical Lead for a search app:

- I held responsibility for technical direction, tech-debt prioritisation, and code quality standards;
- I worked with Product Development and Project Leads to translate the business and technical requirements for new features into Jira issues for implementation by the developers in London, Chicago, and Shanghai;
- I joined remote and in-person interview panels for potential interns, graduate developers, and senior front-end developers.

In addition to my main project work:

- I designed and reviewed component APIs for the front-end component libraries, emphasising backwards-compatibility and extensibility;
- I helped found the "Front-End Chapter", a cross US-UK team group dedicated to sharing knowledge and best practices in front-end development;
- I gave talks on Visual Regressions testing, TypeScript, Styled Components, and design patterns in React;
- I held a half-day introductory workshop on React and our internal UI Components library;
- I organised and participated in cross-company coding competitions on competitive game-playing Als and image classification challenges;
- I ran a lunchtime "Coding Club" teaching front-end frameworks and TDD.

Education

2011-15: Queen Mary University of London, London, UK

Degree: Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Theoretical Physics (String Theory)

As a graduate student, I authored <u>multiple papers</u> published in peer-reviewed academic journals, gave talks at multiple academic institutions, and taught Physics undergraduates.

2007–11: University of Cambridge (Christ's College), Cambridge, UK

Degree: BA with MMath, Mathematical Tripos, First Class/Honours Pass

Interests

Coding

- Contributed to various open source JavaScript projects
- Attended conferences and meetups on TypeScript, React, and GraphQL
- Experimented in personal projects with Svelte, GraphQL, Apollo, NumPy, and TensorFlow

Other

Board games, heavy metal, folk, sci-fi, fantasy, festivals, travelling, running, craft beer